<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>9. 关于安全性的考量 on Autumn Navigation</title>
    <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 9. 关于安全性的考量 on Autumn Navigation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>cn</language><atom:link href="/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>9.1. 会话的可关联性</title>
      <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.1_Session_Linkability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.1_Session_Linkability/</guid>
      <description>Use of TLS session tickets allows servers and possibly other entities to correlate connections made by the same client; see Section 4.5 for details.
TLS会话票据的使用使得服务器或其他实体能够将同一客户端创建的连接相互关联起来；有关细节详见第4.5章。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9.2. 与0-RTT相关的重放攻击</title>
      <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.2_Replay_Attacks_with_0-RTT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.2_Replay_Attacks_with_0-RTT/</guid>
      <description>As described in Section 8 of [TLS13], use of TLS early data comes with an exposure to replay attack. The use of 0-RTT in QUIC is similarly vulnerable to replay attack.
正如《TLS13》的第8章所述，使用了TLS早期数据就会被暴露于重放攻击之下。QUIC的0-RTT有着类似的风险。
Endpoints MUST implement and use the replay protections described in [TLS13], however it is recognized that these protections are imperfect. Therefore, additional consideration of the risk of replay is needed.
终端必须实现并使用《TLS13》中描述的重放保护，然而这些保护并不被认为是完美的。因此，对于重放攻击的风险还需要更多考量。
QUIC is not vulnerable to replay attack, except via the application protocol information it might carry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9.3. 数据包放大攻击的抵御</title>
      <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.3_Packet_Reflection_Attack_Mitigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.3_Packet_Reflection_Attack_Mitigation/</guid>
      <description>A small ClientHello that results in a large block of handshake messages from a server can be used in packet reflection attacks to amplify the traffic generated by an attacker.
如果一条较小的ClientHello（客户端问候）能使得服务器响应巨大的握手消息，它就能被用于数据包放大攻击，放大攻击者生成的流量。
QUIC includes three defenses against this attack. First, the packet containing a ClientHello MUST be padded to a minimum size. Second, if responding to an unverified source address, the server is forbidden to send more than three times as many bytes as the number of bytes it has received (see Section 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9.4. 对头部保护的分析</title>
      <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.4_Header_Protection_Analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.4_Header_Protection_Analysis/</guid>
      <description>[NAN] analyzes authenticated encryption algorithms that provide nonce privacy, referred to as &amp;ldquo;Hide Nonce&amp;rdquo; (HN) transforms. The general header protection construction in this document is one of those algorithms (HN1). Header protection is applied after the packet protection AEAD, sampling a set of bytes (sample) from the AEAD output and encrypting the header field using a pseudorandom function (PRF) as follows:
《NAN》分析了许多能保护随机数的认证加密算法，它们被称为“随机数隐藏”（HN）转换。本文档中的头部保护构建方法大体上可以算作是这些算法中的其中一种（HN1）。头部保护会在数据包保护AEAD之后被应用，它从AEAD的输出中采样一组字节样本（表达式中的sample），并以此方法使用伪随机函数（表达式中的PRF）来加密头部字段：
protected_field = field XOR PRF(hp_key, sample) 
 The header protection variants in this document use a pseudorandom permutation (PRP) in place of a generic PRF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9.5. 头部保护的计时侧信道</title>
      <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.5_Header_Protection_Timing_Side_Channels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.5_Header_Protection_Timing_Side_Channels/</guid>
      <description>An attacker could guess values for packet numbers or Key Phase and have an endpoint confirm guesses through timing side channels. Similarly, guesses for the packet number length can be tried and exposed. If the recipient of a packet discards packets with duplicate packet numbers without attempting to remove packet protection, they could reveal through timing side channels that the packet number matches a received packet. For authentication to be free from side channels, the entire process of header protection removal, packet number recovery, and packet protection removal MUST be applied together without timing and other side channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9.6. 密钥的隔离性</title>
      <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.6_Key_Diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.6_Key_Diversity/</guid>
      <description>In using TLS, the central key schedule of TLS is used. As a result of the TLS handshake messages being integrated into the calculation of secrets, the inclusion of the QUIC transport parameters extension ensures that the handshake and 1-RTT keys are not the same as those that might be produced by a server running TLS over TCP. To avoid the possibility of cross-protocol key synchronization, additional measures are provided to improve key separation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9.7. 随机性</title>
      <link>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.7_Randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/RFC9001_Chinese_Translation/Security_Considerations/9.7_Randomness/</guid>
      <description>QUIC depends on endpoints being able to generate secure random numbers, both directly for protocol values such as the connection ID, and transitively via TLS. See [RFC4086] for guidance on secure random number generation.
QUIC依赖于终端生成安全的随机数的能力，这项能力既会被直接用在协议里的一些值上，如连接ID，也会经由TLS被使用到。有关安全的随机数生成的指导，详见《RFC4086》。</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
